Where there's a will, there's a weapon.
Lord of War is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Andrew Niccol.
Yuri Orlov is a globetrotting arms dealer and, through some of the deadliest war zones, he struggles to stay one step ahead of a relentless
Interpol agent, his business rivals and even some of his customers who include many of the world's most notorious dictators.
Finally, he must also face his own conscience.
Yuri Orlov, played by Nicolas Cage.
Ava Fontaine Orlov, played by Bridget Moynahan.
Vitaly Orlov, played by Jared Leto.
Jack Valentine, played by Ethan Hawke.
Andre Baptiste Sr., played by Eamonn Walker.
Simeon Weisz, played by Ian Holm.
Lord of War is a 2005 crime drama film written and directed by Andrew Niccol.
It stars Nicolas Cage, Jared Leto, Bridget Moynahan, Ethan
Hawke, and Eamonn Walker in primary roles.
The plot follows an unscrupulous Ukrainian-American man named Yuri Orlov (portrayed by Cage) as he participates in the
global arms trafficking industry in the years preceding and succeeding the dissolution of the Soviet Union.
The film opens with arms dealer Yuri Orlov  delivering a direct-to-camera monologue against a backdrop
of spent bullet casings: "There are over 550 million firearms in worldwide circulation.
That's one firearm for every twelve people on the planet.
The only question is: How do we arm the other eleven?" This line immediately
establishes the film's cynical tone and central theme of the global arms trade.
The film was released in the United States by Lions Gate Films on September 16, 2005, and received mixed reviews, with many praising the opening
sequence's messaging and Cage's performance as Yuri, but garnered criticism for its lack of focus and handling of Yuri's character.
It grossed US$72.6 million at the box office,
making it a financial disappointment.
A sequel is currently in development.
The film explores themes of hotel, new york city, civil war, dictator, cold war.
The tone is emotional and intense.